Guide to the John Lowenthal Papers TAM.190
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Subject Files, 1942-2003; 81036
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Memorandum in Support of Defendant's Motion for a New Trial Under Rule 33 on the Ground of Newly Discovered Evidence, 1952; cuid8591; 81377 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Appellant's Brief, Nov 1952; cuid8592; 81376 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Appendix to Appellant's Brief, Jul 22, 1952; cuid8593; 81375 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Consolidated Index of Record, undated; cuid8594; 81374 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Petition for Rehearing, undated; cuid8595; 81373 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume I, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8596; 81372 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume II, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8597; 81371 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume III, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8598; 81370 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume IV, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8599; 81369 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume V, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8600; 81368 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume VI, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8601; 81367 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume VII, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8602; 81366 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume VIII, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8603; 81365 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume IX, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8604; 81364 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, On Appeal, Transcript of Record, Volume X, Jan 25, 1950; cuid8605; 81363 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Second Supplemental Affidavit, 1952; cuid8606; 81362 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, May 31, 1949; cuid8607; 81361 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 6, 1949; cuid8608; 81360 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 9, 1949; cuid8609; 81359 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 14, 1949; cuid8610; 81358 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 20, 1949; cuid8611; 81357 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 23, 1949; cuid8612; 81356 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 28, 1948; cuid8613; 81355 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jun 30, 1948; cuid8614; 81354 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Hiss Case: U.S.A. v. Alger Hiss, Stenographer's Minutes, Jul 6, 1949; cuid8615; 81353 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Hiss Case: Woodstock Typewriter, 1940s; cuid8616; 81352 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - The Hiss Case Revisited (JL): Handwritten Notes, undated; cuid8617; 81351 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - The Hiss Case Revisited (JL): Typescript, undated; cuid8618; 81350 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Introduction (Chapter 1), 1995; cuid8619; 81349 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Coram Nobis, 1987; cuid8620; 81348 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Drafts and Comments, 1987; cuid8621; 81347 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Notes, re:, 1982, 1992-1996; cuid8622; 81346 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Russia, 1998; cuid8623; 81345 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): The Typewriter, 1987; cuid8624; 81344 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Hiss Manuscript (JL): Whittaker Chambers' Homosexuality, undated; cuid8625; 81343 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Hiss, Tony: Re: Laughing Last, undated, 1976-1977; cuid8626; 81342 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Hiss, Tony: Writings, 1995-1996, 2001; cuid8627; 81341 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Hobson, Timothy, 1949-1950, 1968, 1977; cuid8628; 81340 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Hofstra University: International Conference on Harry S. Truman, Apr 14, 1983-Apr 16, 1983; cuid8629; 81339 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Horowitz, Sol, 1979-1980; cuid8630; 81338 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Howgate, James C.: HUAC Reports, Re:, Mar 1963; cuid8631; 81337 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Hunt, Howard: Grand Jury Testimony, May 2, 1973; cuid8632; 81336 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Ilyashov, Anatoli Michael: Correspondence and Letter to the Editor, 1992-1994; cuid8633; 81335 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Intelligence and National Security: "Venona and Alger Hiss", 2000; cuid8634; 81334 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Kalugin, Oleg Danielovich: Clippings and Correspondence, 1992; cuid8635; 81333 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Kenan, George B., 1972, 1977, 1996-1999; cuid8636; 81332 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Kenshaw, Alex: The Guardian, 1992-1994; cuid8637; 81331 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Kinsley, Michael and Arthur Lubow: "Alger Hiss and the Smoking Gun Fallacy" (Washington Monthly), Oct 1975; cuid8638; 81330 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Kraft, Marion: Last Will and Testament, re:, 1982-1984; cuid8639; 81329 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Kraft, Marion: Motion Picture Editors, Local 771, 1978-1982; cuid8640; 81328 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Krieger, Sam: Chambers/Hiss, Re:, 1977-1982; cuid8641; 81327 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Krieger, Sam: Lawsuit Re: Perjury, 1978; cuid8642; 81326 (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Lake, Anthony: CIA, 1977-1978; cuid8643; 81325 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Lamphere, Robert J.: Book Excerpts and Notes, re:, 1983, 1986; cuid8644; 81324 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Leab, Daniel J.: "United We Eat: The Creation and Organization of the Unemployed Councils in 1930" (Labor History), Fall 1967; cuid8645; 81323 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Lee, Duncan, Eleanor and John: Correspondence and Letter to the Editor (New York Times), 1999; cuid8646; 81322 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Lee Pressman and David Witt, Typescript, 1998-1999; cuid8647; 81321 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Letters of Support: Re: Hiss, 1992-1993; cuid8648; 81320 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Letters to the Editor: Drafts, 1973; 1986; 1991-1993; cuid8649; 81319 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Letters to the Editor: Drafts, 1994; cuid8650; 81318 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Letters to the Editor: Drafts, 1995-2003; cuid8651; 81317 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Letters to the Editor: Published, 1992-2001; cuid8652; 81316 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Letters to the Editor: Re: Alger Hiss Obituaries, 1996; cuid8653; 81315 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Levin, David: Articles and Obituaries, 1976, 1979, 1993-1997; cuid8654; 81314 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Levin, David: Correspondence, 1993-1998; cuid8655; 81313 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Levine, Isaac Don, 1940-1999; cuid8656; 81312 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Lockwood, Manice, III: Correspondence, undated, 1950-1953, 1969-1994; cuid8657; 81311 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Lowe, Richard H.: Correspondence, 1976, 1979; cuid8658; 81310 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Lowe, Richard H.: "Fallen Warrior of Reform: Jerome N. Frank as General Counsel for the Agricultural Adjustment Administration," Class Paper, undated; cuid8659; 81309 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Lowenthal, Anne: Correspondence, 1981, 2001; cuid8660; 81308 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Lowenthal, David: Correspondence, 1977-1980; cuid8661; 81307 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Lowenthal, Max, undated; cuid8662; 81306 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Lowenthal, Max: and Alger Hiss, 1995, 1998; cuid8663; 81305 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Lowenthal, Max: Correspondence, 1940s; cuid8664; 81304 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Lowenthal, Max: Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) File, Jun 7, 1999; cuid8665; 81303 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 1, undated; cuid8666; 81302 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 6, undated; cuid8667; 81301 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 6 Bulky 576, undated; cuid8668; 81300 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 7, undated; cuid8669; 81299 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 8, undated; cuid8670; 81298 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File, Section 9, Part 1, undated; cuid8671; 81297 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Section 9, Part 2), undated; cuid8672; 81296 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Sections 9 and 10), undated; cuid8673; 81295 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Section 11), undated; cuid8674; 81294 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Section 12, Part 1), undated; cuid8675; 81293 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Section 12, Part 2), undated; cuid8676; 81292 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Lowenthal, Max: FOIA File (Sections 13 and 14), undated; cuid8677; 81291 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - MacArthur, John: Re: Harpers, 1992-1996, 2002-2003; cuid8678; 81290 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Marbury, William, 1976-1978, 1988; cuid8679; 81289 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Mark, Eduard: Reply from JL re: "Alger Hiss, The Perfect Victim", 2003; cuid8680; 81288 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Mark, Eduard: Reply from JL re: "Who Was Venona's 'Ales'? Cryptoanalysis and the Hiss Case", 2003; cuid8681; 81287 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Marshall Plan, 1997-1999; cuid8682; 81286 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Martino, Rose, 1966, 1969; cuid8683; 81285 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - McDowell, John: Correspondence, Jul 23, 1956; cuid8684; 81284 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Merillat, Herbert Christopher: Correspondence, 1995; cuid8685; 81283 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Miller, Larry: "Clarence Evan Pickett and the Alger Hiss Case," Typescript, undated; cuid8686; 81282 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Moor, Paul: Correspondence, 1992-1994; cuid8687; 81281 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Moore, William: Correspondence, 1988; cuid8688; 81280 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - The Movie, Typescript, Mar 1998; cuid8689; 81279 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Murphy, Robert C.: "The Hiss Case: Insights," Re:, undated, 1992-1993; cuid8690; 81278 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Murphy, Thomas F.: Correspondence, 1972, 1977-1978; cuid8691; 81277 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Murphy, Thomas: "Summation to the Jury: People of the United States v. Alger Hiss" (Plain Talk) Aug 1949, cuid8692; 81276 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Musmanno, Michael A.: That Chambers Book: With Comment on Communism, Alger Hiss and the State of Our Times, Pamphlet, undated; cuid8693; 81275 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Nation: Articles/Editorials, 1976, 1992, 1994; cuid8694; 81274 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Nation Institute: "Investigative Reporting after the Cold War," Conference, Moscow State University, Sep 4, 1992-Sep 7, 1992; cuid8695; 81273 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Nation Institute: Press Reactions to Nation Institute's Cold War Archive Hiss Project, Clippings, Oct 1992-Mar 1993; cuid8696; 81272 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - National Emergency Civil Liberties Committee: Correspondence, 1980, 1983; cuid8697; 81271 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - National Popular Government League: Report on the Illegal Practices of the U.S. Department of Justice, Pamphlet, May 1920; cuid8698; 81270 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - National Review: Re: Hiss, 1993; cuid8699; 81269 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Navasky, Victor: Correspondence, 1978-2001; cuid8700; 81268 (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Navasky, Victor: Re: Communism, Hiss, 1978, 1996, 2000-2001; cuid8701; 81267 (Box 17, Folder 27)
  - Nedelkoff, Robert: Correspondence, undated, 1994; cuid8702; 81266 (Box 17, Folder 28)
  - Nelson, Lawrence J.: Correspondence, 1979; cuid8703; 81265 (Box 17, Folder 29)
  - New Criterion: "Notes and Comments," re: Hiss, Dec 1992; cuid8704; 81264 (Box 17, Folder 30)
  - Newmyer, Jacqueline: "The Vindication of an Innocent Man", 1993; cuid8705; 81263 (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Newshour with Jim Lehrer: Transcript re: Nixon Tapes, Jan 2, 1997; cuid8706; 81262 (Box 17, Folder 32)
  - Newsweek: Re: Hiss, 1992-1993; cuid8707; 81261 (Box 17, Folder 33)
  - Nezavisimaya Gazeta, 1992-1993; cuid8708; 81260 (Box 17, Folder 34)
  - Nixon, Richard: Re: Hiss, undated, 1992-1993; cuid8709; 81259 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Nixon, Richard: "The Hiss Case: A Lesson for the American People," Speech, Jan 26, 1950; cuid8710; 81258 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Nixon, Richard: Six Crises, Excerpts, 1962; cuid8711; 81257 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Nixon's Manipulations in the Hiss-Chambers Case (JL): Typescript, undated; cuid8712; 81256 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Notes: Handwritten, re: Hiss Books, undated; cuid8713; 81255 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Oates, Titus: Handwritten Notes re:, undated, 2003; cuid8714; 81254 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Opinions-Editorials (JL), 1962, 1996, 2002; cuid8715; 81253 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Osann, H. E.: "The Alger Hiss Case," Correspondence and Typescript, 1964-1965; cuid8716; 81252 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Piel, Gerard: Clash of Civilizations, re:, 1999; cuid8717; 81251 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Pierce, Edward: Re: "Ales", undated, 1997-1998; cuid8718; 81250 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Pigman, Ward, 1948, 1977; cuid8719; 81249 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Political Cartoons: Dreyfus, Hiss, undated, 1950; cuid8720; 81248 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Political Cartoons: Permission to Reprint, 1970-2000; cuid8721; 81247 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Pollack, Louis: U.S.A. v. Carlos Ivan Llera Plaza, Wilfredo Acosta, Victor Rodriguez, 2002; cuid8722; 81246 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Popkin, Julie: Correspondence, 1992-1993; cuid8723; 81245 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Powers, Thomas, Re: Ales, undated; cuid8724; 81244 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Prelin, Igor, 1992; cuid8725; 81243 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Public Citizen Litigation Group: Re: Hiss, May 14, 1999; cuid8726; 81242 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Public Relations: Re: Hiss, undated, 1986, 1992-1993; cuid8727; 81241 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Publishers and Agents: Correspondence, 2001-2002; cuid8728; 81240 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Quinn, Hannah and James: Correspondence, 1995; cuid8729; 81239 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Rabinowitz, Victor: Correspondence, Nov 10, 1982; cuid8730; 81238 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Reuben, William A.: Correspondence, 1970-1989; cuid8731; 81237 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Reuben, William A.: Handwritten Notes, undated; cuid8732; 81236 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Introduction, undated; cuid8733; 81235 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 1, undated; cuid8734; 81234 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 2, undated; cuid8735; 81233 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 3, undated; cuid8736; 81232 (Box 18, Folder 28)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 4, undated; cuid8737; 81231 (Box 18, Folder 29)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 6, undated; cuid8738; 81230 (Box 18, Folder 30)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 8, undated; cuid8739; 81229 (Box 18, Folder 31)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 9, undated; cuid8740; 81228 (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 10, undated; cuid8741; 81227 (Box 18, Folder 33)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 11, undated; cuid8742; 81226 (Box 18, Folder 34)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 12, undated; cuid8743; 81225 (Box 18, Folder 35)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 13, undated; cuid8744; 81224 (Box 18, Folder 36)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 14, undated; cuid8745; 81223 (Box 18, Folder 37)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 17, undated; cuid8746; 81222 (Box 18, Folder 38)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 18, undated; cuid8747; 81221 (Box 18, Folder 39)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 21, undated; cuid8748; 81220 (Box 18, Folder 40)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 22, undated; cuid8749; 81219 (Box 18, Folder 41)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 24, undated; cuid8750; 81218 (Box 18, Folder 42)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 25, undated; cuid8751; 81217 (Box 18, Folder 43)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 26, Dec 9, 1998; cuid8752; 81216 (Box 18, Folder 44)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 27, Nov 18, 1998; cuid8753; 81215 (Box 18, Folder 45)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 28, Apr 16, 1999; cuid8754; 81214 (Box 18, Folder 46)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 29, Aug 19, 1999; cuid8755; 81213 (Box 18, Folder 47)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 30, Nov 1, 2000; cuid8756; 81212 (Box 18, Folder 48)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 31, Nov 24, 1999; cuid8757; 81211 (Box 18, Folder 49)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 32, Apr 2, 2000; cuid8758; 81210 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 33, Oct 2000; cuid8759; 81209 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 34, undated; cuid8760; 81208 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Reuben, William A.: Hiss/Chambers Typescript, Chapter 36, undated; cuid8761; 81207 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Reuben, William A.: Letters to the Editor, 1996, 1999; cuid8762; 81206 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Reuben, William A.: Nixon Typescript, Chapters 1-5, undated; cuid8763; 81205 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Reuben, William A.: Nixon Typescript, Chapters 6-8; 10-13, undated; cuid8764; 81204 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Reuben, William A.: Nixon Typescript, Chapters 14-17, undated; cuid8765; 81203 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Reuben, William A.: "Whittaker Chambers: An American Hero," Typescript, undated; cuid8766; 81202 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Riptide Communications: Correspondence, 1992; cuid8767; 81201 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Risen, James: Correspondence, 1993, 2003; cuid8768; 81200 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Roberts, R. M.: Correspondence, 1993; cuid8769; 81199 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Roddick, Ellen: Correspondence, Nov 1997; cuid8770; 81198 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Rodell, Fred: "Was Alger Hiss Framed?" (The Progressive), Apr 1952; cuid8771; 81197 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Rogers, Bill: Correspondence, 1983-1984; cuid8772; 81196 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Romerstein, Herbert: The Venona Secrets, re:, 1992-2001; cuid8773; 81195 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Rosenberg Case, 1951, 1962, 1974-1993; cuid8774; 81194 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Rosenwald, Harold: Correspondence, 1972-1977; cuid8775; 81193 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Rosenwald, Harold: "In the Matter of Alger Hiss," (Harvard Law School Bulletin), Fall 1975; cuid8776; 81192 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Roulhac, George Norman: FBI File, undated; cuid8777; 81191 (Box 19, Folder 19a)
  - Russian Archives: Conference and Trip, 1991-1992, 1998; cuid8778; 81190 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Russian Archives: Re: Hiss, 1992-1993; cuid8779; 81189 (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Russian General Says Hiss Was No Spy (JL): Notes and Typescript, 1992; cuid8780; 81188 (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Ryan, Clarke Sylvester, 1950, 1977; cuid8781; 81187 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Sachs, Nannette Pierson: Correspondence, Dec 23, 1996; cuid8782; 81186 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Salant, Stephen: Correspondence, 1976-2000; cuid8783; 81185 (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Salant, Stephen: Writings re: Hiss, undated, 1974; cuid8784; 81184 (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Sanders, Bernard: Correspondence, re: Hiss, Aug 31, 1992; cuid8785; 81183 (Box 19, Folder 27)
  - Sandilands, Roger J.: Re: Lauchlin Currie, 1999-2000; cuid8786; 81182 (Box 19, Folder 28)
  - Sayre, Nora, undated, 1998; cuid8787; 81181 (Box 19, Folder 29)
  - Scales, Junius: Handwritten Notes, re:, 1977; cuid8788; 81180 (Box 19, Folder 30)
  - Schmidt, Maria: Article Re: Hiss, 1993; cuid8789; 81179 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Schweizer, Werner: "Noel Field: The Fictitious Spy," Typescript, 1996; cuid8790; 81178 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Shapiro, Meyer: Re: Hiss, 1948-1949, 1967, 1977-1987; cuid8791; 81177 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - Shattuck, John H.F.: Letter to the Editor, re: Hiss, Mar 19, 1976; cuid8792; 81176 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Shaw, Elizabeth: Re: Vincent Shaw, 1986-1987; cuid8793; 81175 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Sheehy, Margaret: "Joyous and Sorrowful," Typescript, 1984; cuid8794; 81174 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - Shelley, Alexandra: Article Re: Hiss (East Hampton Star), 1993; cuid8795; 81173 (Box 19, Folder 37)
  - Silvermaster, Nathan Gregory: Handwritten Notes, re:, 2000; cuid8796; 81172 (Box 19, Folder 38)
  - Simes, Dmitri, 1993-1994, 1998; cuid8797; 81171 (Box 19, Folder 39)
  - Simon Meyer and Son, Inc.: Insurance Policy, 1980; cuid8798; 81170 (Box 19, Folder 40)
  - Smith, John Chabot: Correspondence, 1976; cuid8799; 81169 (Box 19, Folder 41)
  - Smith, John Chabot: Debate with Allen Weinstein, Opening Statement, Apr 3, 1976; cuid8800; 81168 (Box 19, Folder 42)
  - Soviet Historiography on the Hiss Case (JL): Typescript, 1994; cuid8801; 81167 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Speaker Program, 2000-2003; cuid8802; 81166 (Box 19, Folder 44)
  - Spectator: Correspondence re: Hiss Article, 1996-2000; cuid8803; 81165 (Box 19, Folder 45)
  - Stephens, Robert A. v. William F. Yeomens, undated; cuid8804; 81164 (Box 19, Folder 46)
  - Stevens, Alexander (aka Jay Peters/Alexander Goldberger): Correspondence, May 9, 1949; cuid8805; 81163 (Box 19, Folder 47)
  - Stevenson, Matthew: Correspondence, 1992-1993; cuid8806; 81162 (Box 19, Folder 48)
  - Stevenson, Matthew: "Dealing in Russia" (The American Scholar), 1993; cuid8807; 81161 (Box 19, Folder 49)
  - Stevenson, Matthew: "Letter from Serbia" (The American Scholar), 1992; cuid8808; 81160 (Box 19, Folder 50)
  - Stoessel, Frederic: Correspondence, Jul 1975; cuid8809; 81159 (Box 19, Folder 51)
  - Stoskopf, Alan: "The Cold War at Home: The Remarkable Case of Alger Hiss," School Paper, 1983; cuid8810; 81158 (Box 19, Folder 52)
  - Stripling, Robert: Pumpkin Film, 1977, 1980; cuid8811; 81157 (Box 19, Folder 53)
  - Summers, Anthony: Correspondence, 1998-2000; cuid8812; 81156 (Box 19, Folder 54)
  - Tanenhaus, Sam, 1992-1993, 1997, 1999; cuid8813; 81155 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Telephone Tapping, Aug 24, 1949; cuid8814; 81154 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Toledano, Ralph de: FBI Reports, 1949; cuid8815; 81153 (Box 20, Folder 2a)
  - Travel: Trip to Soviet Union, 1992; cuid8816; 81152 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Bibliographic Notes, undated; cuid8817; 81151 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Borovik, Artiom, 1992-1993; cuid8818; 81150 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Clippings, 1981; cuid8819; 81149 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Clippings, Negatives and Positives, 1940-1959; cuid8820; 81148 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: British Universities Film and Video Council, 2000-2003; cuid8821; 81147 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Chambers, Esther, 1977, 1986; cuid8822; 81146 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Cooke, Alistair, 1979-1980; cuid8823; 81145 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Correspondence, re:, 1977-1979; cuid8824; 81144 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Correspondence, re:, 1980-1981; cuid8825; 81143 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Day, James, Nov 1, 1977; cuid8826; 81142 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: de Antonio, Emile, 1976-1979; cuid8827; 81141 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Direct Cinema, 1992-1999; cuid8828; 81140 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Directors Note and Film Transcript, 2003; cuid8829; 81139 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Trials of Alger Hiss: Endnotes and Film Notes, undated; cuid8830; 81138 (Box 20, Folder 17)